原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
翻译:  赛太公祝饺子生日快乐
翻译:  Eunice    洗七里   zoeyyyyy
校对:  终于是红V赛太公
时间轴:  三水
后期:  瓜瓜    总监： 怀念浓子的瓜瓜
打开微信   扫描左侧二维码
或搜索公众号:    美剧炸了
了解最新影视资讯字幕信息
摩  登
家  庭
第八季 第十三集
最新海外影视剧下载
好了
Okay.
螺丝刀
Screwdriver?
备用螺丝刀
Backup screwdriver.
我家族是代代相传的能工巧匠
I come from a long line of handy men.
以前我爸爸什么都自己修好
My dad used to fix everything --
修剪草机  修车子  还阉[修]猫
lawnmowers, cars, our cat.
所以当维修工人试图坑我后
So it made sense that I tackled the clothes dryer
我自然就决定自己修烘衣机
after the repair guy tried to rip me off.
我才不要花350刀
I'm not paying $350
来修一个只值28刀的湿度传感器
for a moisture sensor that costs $28.
我会自己修好它
I'll fix it myself.
维修工作很复杂的
It's a complicated job.
你知道我以前在俄罗斯是干什么的吗
You know what I did back in Russia?
我知道啊
Yeah, yeah, I know.
你是个医生  要不就科学家
You were a doctor or a scientist.
我是修烘衣机的
I fixed dryers.
我意思是  我干这一行很久了
I've been doing this a long time is my point.
本大爷可不是任人宰割的软柿子
Well, your Phil Dunphy is no push-over.
恐怕要坚定地拒绝你了
I'm afraid it's a hard nyet.
其实这些衣服也够干净了
I guess these are clean enough.
我很快就能把这机器修好  亲爱的
I'll have this thing running in no time, honey.
我有维修教学影片
I have an instructional video,
而且我把拆下来的每个零件都做了标记
and I'm labeling each part as I take it out.
"右后角
"Right-back corner.
弯弯的小东西
Tiny elbow-y thingy.
我的右手边  即是烘衣机的左边"
My right. Dryer left."
你们不能到别的地方修吗
Can't you do this somewhere else?
是啊  烘衣机才是该自己搬出去住的那个人
Right, the dryer's the one that needs to get its own place.
宝贝  反正你也该起床了  我们要上烹饪课
Honey, you have to be up anyhow. We've got our cooking class.
我想早点到  抢占前排的炉子
I want to get there early and grab a stove up front.
天啊  妈妈  你跟那个厨师
Oh, my God, Mom. You and that chef.
你能不能轻点骚
Keep it in your apron.
妈妈很迷恋电视上那个大厨查尔斯·杜蒙特
Mom's obsessed with this TV chef Charles Dumont.
她每天都收看他的节目
She watches his show every day.
不过她好像也没有专心听
Not sure she listens, though.
加少许糖
A pinch of sugar,
你的味蕾就会像法国人一样弃械投降
and your taste buds will surrender like the French.
抱歉  这个哏有点太干...奶酪了
I'm sorry, that joke was a little fromage-y.
-他说盐吗  -是糖啦  糖
- Did he say salt? - Sugar. Sugar. Sugar.
我还真想让他尝尝我有多甜呢
Mmm! I'd love to give him some sugar.
但我很肯定他刚刚说的是盐  宝贝
But I'm pretty sure he said salt here, baby.
-试试味道  -不要
- Take taste. - Oh, no. Aah!
-嗯  -好吃吗
- Yeah. - Yeah?
确实别有"风味"
That's got something in it.
烹饪搭配的酒快喝完了
Oh, almost out of cookin' juice.
好了  下一步非常重要
All right, the next step is very important.
你真的不用暂停吗
You sure you don't want to pause it?
不用
Oh, no, I'm good.
不能再这样下去了
We got to fix this.
我们不能告诉她  她做的菜有多难吃
We can't tell her how bad her food is,
因为那会让她伤心欲绝
because that would destroy her.
所以当我得知杜蒙特大厨要来城里
So when I found out Chef Dumont was coming to town,
我就给我俩报名上课  让他来当坏人
I signed us up for his class so he could do it.
场面挺激烈的是吧
I know. Pretty intense, huh?
现在我就把传感器
Now I just grab the sensor
放到...
and put it --
里面棉絮挺多啊
Oh, a little linty.
早知道应该先清空...
I probably should have emptied...
零件都没事吧
Aah! Are the parts okay?
没事
Yeah, they're fine.
谢天谢地
Oh, thank God.
我不知道...
I don't know --
好了  乔  把球投过来吧
All right, Joe. Fire it in here, buddy.
好棒
Ooh! Yes!
太好了  我不用跟这个儿子也说
Good! Now I don't have to tell another son
有些男孩的天赋跟其他男孩不同
that some boys have different gifts.
干得好  小强棒
Good job there, slugger.
这是怎么回事  歌洛莉亚
What the hell's going on here, Gloria?
我觉得自己好像已经死了
I feel like I died.
我是以游魂视角在看我再婚的家人
I'm watching my family as a ghost.
别傻了  如果你真死了
Don't be silly. If that happened,
我早就已经把这些家具全换掉了
I would have changed all this furniture.
我请了盖里教练
I hired Coach Gary.
他会教乔怎么投球
He's gonna teach Joe how to throw.
乔是他们队里最弱的一个
Joe is the worst on his team.
我听见了哦
I hear you!
你儿子交给我保准没问题  杰
Your son's in good hands, Jay.
去年我带领队伍拿下了冠军
I led my team to the championship last year.
本来幼儿组不该计分的
We weren't supposed to keep score,
但我在脑子里偷记下来了
but I did in my head.
这太离谱了
This is crazy.
这种事情孩子应该跟自己爸爸学
Kid's supposed to learn the stuff from his dad,
例如打棒球  开车
baseball, how to drive a car,
还有怎么跟新泽西州人打架
how to fight a guy from Jersey.
当你觉得你已经拿走了他的刀...
If you think you took his knife...
他身上还有一把
He's got another one.
乔的投球方式都是跟杰学的
Joe learned to throw by copying Jay,
可是杰投得乱七八糟  因为他肩膀不好
but Jay throws all crazy because of his bad shoulder.
像这样投  孩子
Like this, buddy.
我勒个...
Son of a...!
乔在尿尿时会用口哨吹
It's the same reason Joe whistles
《感伤之旅》也是这个原因
"Sentimental Journey" when he pees.
1944年发行的歌曲
你看起来人挺好的
You seem like a nice guy and all,
但我来教他就行了
but I got this.
没问题  盖瑞教练懂的
Hey, no sweat. Coach Gary gets it.
别忘了带走你的球
Hey, uh, don't forget your ball.
没关系  杰  有些男孩的天赋跟其他男孩不同
It's okay, Jay. Some boys have different gifts.
-我去开门  -好的  谢谢
- Let me get the door. - Ok, thank you.
你好  有什么事吗
Hi. Can I help you?
我来找莉莉
I'm here for Lily.
我知道这一天迟早会来
I always knew this day would come.
她应该不是来认亲的
Probably not what she's here for.
你怎么会认识我们女儿
How do you know our daughter?
不认识  她雇我来打扫卫生
I don't. She hired me for a cleaning job.
啥
Oh. What?
真准时啊
Wow. Right on time.
等一下  莉莉  你请了清洁工吗
Wait, Lily, did you hire a cleaning lady?
是啊  用你手机上的应用请的
Yeah, with an app on your phone.
爸爸说我的房间乱得跟猪窝一样
Daddy said my room was a pig sty.
我们回头再讨论你对猪的这个
Okay, we'll double back to that unnecessary
没有必要且有违事实的辱骂
and inaccurate slam on pigs.
而且我想小爸的意思是叫你自己打扫房间
And I think daddy meant for you to clean your room.
我们不能让你帮她打扫房间
We can't have you cleaning our daughter's room.
这样会传递错误的信息
It just -- It sends the wrong message.
我们也可以给你们差评的  知道吗
We get to review you guys, too, you know.
你去打扫房间
Go clean your room.
这不公平  你们什么都用手机应用解决
It's not fair. You guys use apps for everything.
我们才没有
No, we don't.
这个嘛...
Well...
好吧  我们出去吃饭时会用"优步"叫车
Okay, there's Uber for when we eat out...
在家吃饭会用"美团"叫外卖
and Postmates when we eat at.
各种家务就交给"寻人理事"找帮手
And TaskGrabBag for stuff around the house.
"洗衣到府"  "车位地图"
And Washio and ParkMe
还有那个请专人来
and the one where the guy comes over
帮家里壁炉生火的应用
and builds a fire in your fireplace.
"专人取火"啊  我喜欢那个
Oh, LogBuddy. I love LogBuddy.
我们必须以身作则
We need to start leading by example.
从现在开始  我们都要更自力更生
From now on, we're all gonna be a little more self-reliant.
首先  我自己来生火
For starters, I'll build the fires.
可是"专人取火"那个人会打扮成猛男伐木工
But the LogBuddy guy comes dressed as a lumberjack.
我也有猛男法兰绒衬衫啊
I have a flannel shirt.
那些多出来的零件到哪里去了
Where are all the extra pieces?
没有多余的  我全装上了
There aren't any. I used every last one.
你是不是丢掉了
Did you throw them away?
你可以直说  我不会生气的
You can tell me. I won't be angry.
我把烘衣机修好了  克莱尔
I fixed the dryer, Claire,
你有幸见证这一奇迹般的时刻
and you get to be here for the moment of truth.
拔掉保险销
Pull the pin.
真的修好了
It works.
我以前都不知道你是如此巧手
I had no idea you were so good with your hands.
很有男子气概
Very manly.
前面我的拇指还被老虎钳夹到了
I pinched my thumb with a pair of pliers earlier.
我都没喊疼
Not a peep.
卢克  你爸和我要上楼去
Luke, daddy and I need to go upstairs
私下谈些事情
to discuss something in private.
去就别废话  快被你们恶心得一生不举了
Just go. You're ruining sex for me.
床单都因为摩擦太激烈起静电了
Oh, we just created some static in these sheets, huh?
-那感觉真是太棒了  -是啊
- That felt amazing. - Yeah.
我深入那台烘衣机把它修了个落花流水
I got all up in that dryer and fixed the hell out of it.
我觉得我无所不能
I feel capable of anything.
你猜怎么着
You know what?
我要展开那项工程了
I'm gonna build it.
-邓菲塔吗  -邓菲塔
- Dunphy Tower? - Dunphy Tower.
邓菲塔
Dunphy Tower --
我的首次商业房地产开发
My first commercial real-estate development.
我从小就梦想能建这样一栋楼
I've been dreaming of building it since I was a kid,
现在终于要成真了
Now it's all happening.
好吧  虽然没了楼顶的蹦床公园
Well, minus the trampoline park on the roof
和通向我死党家的地道
and the tunnel to my best friend's house.
我仍抱着希望能有一根消防队那种钢管
I am still holding out hope for a fireman's pole
可以直接滑到地下停车场
that takes you to the parking garage.
如果你认为自己终于准备好了就做
Well, if you're sure you're finally ready.
我当然准备好了
Of course I am.
我可是刚刚修好了烘衣机的男人
I just fixed the dryer.
那是我这辈子干过的最满足最爽的事了
And it was the most satisfying thing I've ever done.
我起身穿衣服吧
I'll just get dressed, I guesse.
菲尔  我又不是不知道我们在哪
Phil, I know where we are.
刚才是我开的车
I drove.
你知道这是什么地方
You know what this is,
但我要告诉你这里将会变成什么地方
but I'm about to tell you what this could be.
我最不喜欢这种说话方式
This is my least-favorite way of talking.
你所站之处将成为未来的邓菲塔
You are standing on the site of the future Dunphy Tower.
1011平方米的混合应用土地
A quarter acre of mixed-use space
在这片住户高速士绅化的区域
in a rapidly gentrifying neighborhood.
商业房地产开发啊
Commercial real estate, huh?
不像你的作风啊
This is a departure for you.
我每一个细节都考虑过了
I thought about it down to the last detail.
想象一位开心的工人
Imagine a happy worker
从上班坐车方便的办公室下楼来这
coming down from their transit-friendly office
喝杯高级咖啡或者做做瑜伽
for a fancy coffee beverage or yoga,
你猜那边还有什么好东西
and what's that over there?
我希望那只是洋娃娃的断腿
A doll's foot, I hope.
农场直供的狗狗面包店
A farm-to-table dog bakery.
我带斯黛拉去过丹麦村的一家
Ooh, Stella and I went to one of those in Solvang.
我给她买了个法式乳蛋狗饼
She got a quiche.
看起来特好吃  我差点没忍住和她分着吃
It looked so good, I almost split it with her.
我不想逼你投资
I don't want you to feel pressured to invest,
但我想让你知道这不是一时兴起
but I want you to know this isn't a whim.
这件事我已经构想了很久了
I've been thinking about this a lot.
是什么让你决定出手的
What got you off the sidelines?
这可能听起来有点蠢
This is gonna sound silly,
但我今天修好了一台烘衣机
but I fixed a dryer today.
我把它彻底拆开还换了传感器
I took it all apart and swapped out the sensor.
你少来了
Get out of here.
修理工跟我要价350块
The guy wanted 350 bucks.
我自己只花了28
I paid $28.
真厉害
Holy cow!
你为什么等到现在才告诉我这件事
Ho come we haven't been talking about this the whole time?
因为这个项目让我太兴奋了
Because I'm so excited about this project.
我真的认为这会是一项好投资
I-I really think this could be a good investment.
你不必多说了
I don't want to hear any more.
涉及到生意的时候
You're the most cautious guy I know
你是我认识的人中最谨慎的
when it comes to business.
如果你认为这是个金矿  我入伙
If you think this is a slam dunk, I'm in.
真的吗
Really?
因为我已经准备好出价了
'Cause I have an offer ready to go.
你一发话我就发出去
You say the word, I hit "Send."
发吧  我一直在找投资商机
Do it. I've been looking for investment opportunities.
如果你有信心  那我也有信心
If you're confident, I'm confident.
因为你很清楚害我血本无归
Because you know what I'll do to you
你会有什么下场
if you blow my money.
好了  你将学到
All right, you are about to get
关于自力更生的宝贵一课  小姑娘
an important lesson on self-reliance, young lady.
每当他叫我"小姑娘"就知道是来真的
I know he's serious when he calls me "Young lady."
我爸也一样  好啦
My dad did the same thing. Okay.
不再靠我们的手机来摆脱家务了
Okay, no more doing chores with our phones.
我们要亲力亲为
We're going to get our hands dirty.
米奇尔  快来像修体毛一样修整这丛植物
And, Mitchell, you're gonna start right here and manscape this.
-真的吗  好吧  -猜猜你的任务是什么
- Really? Okay. - And guess what you're gonna do?
我能像咱家园丁那样负责往水泥上浇水吗
Can I be in charge of watering the cement like the gardener?
新铺的水泥地也像草皮一样需要浇水养护
不行  你得趴到草地上去
Nope. You're gonna get down on your hands and knees
拔杂草
and pick weeds.
你知道我在你这个年纪都要做些什么吗
You know what I had to do when I was your age?
我得爬遍整块玉米田捡石头
I had to crawl through a cornfield and pick up rocks.
捡不到一百块石头都不让我吃早饭
I couldn't even have breakfast until I picked 100.
我会在头上绑一个手电筒  深入田间
I'd strap a flashlight to my head, and off I'd go.
一块石头  两块石头
One rock, two rocks,
我的天哪
Oh, my God!
这叫戏剧张力好吗
It's called dramatic tension.
-是叫蜂窝  就在那  -什么
- It's called a beehive. Right-Right there. - What?!
没错
Yep. Mm-hmm.
-不  何止是蜂窝  -没错
- Oh, Oh, no. It's worse. - Yeah, yeah, yeah.
-还是马蜂窝呢  -我讨厌马蜂
- Those are wasps. - Oh, I hate wasps!
不  我不是在骂你  佛莱彻先生
No, not you, Mr. Fletcher. The...
拜托
Come on.
歌洛莉亚
Gloria?
菲尔说服我投资了一家小型商场
Phil got me to invest in a mini-mall,
所以你这阵子最好克制点
so you might want to dial back
少买几双鞋
on the shoe purchases for a while.
等一下等一下
One second. One second.
"确认订单"
"Place order."
你刚才说啥  亲爱的
What did you say, baby?
-抽屉修好了  -搞毛啊
- Drawer's fixed. - What the hell?!
别这样一声不响突然吓人
Don't sneak up on people like that.
我很可能一拳揍昏你
I'm liable to have knocked you out.
我表示怀疑
I doubt it.
再说我本来正准备修的
I was gonna fix that, anyway.
你还说要清理屋檐排水沟呢
Ay. Like you were going to clean the gutter?
盖里教练已经清完了
Coach Gary did it already.
一点都不麻烦
It really wasn't a problem.
我不怕高  还有一双大手
I'm not afraid of heights, and I've got big hands.
真是有趣的个人情报
Those are fun details.
这家伙就像想抢走我的生活似的
It's like the guy was trying to steal my life.
我还和迪迪在一起的时候有他在就好了
I wish he'd shown up when I was married to Dede.
我会直接给他配把钥匙
I would have made him a key.
让我送你到门口  尽管貌似
Let me show you out, although you sound like
你已经对我家很熟悉了
you know the place pretty good already.
杰  我周五晚上有个约会
Hey, Jay, I've got a date Friday night.
能把你的车借我吗
Can I borrow your car?
没问题  你可以借你妈的车
Sure, you can borrow your mother's car.
是哪个姑娘这么幸运
Who's the lucky girl?
瑞秋·卡普托
Rachel Caputo.
她和曼尼一起做校报
She and Manny work on the school paper together.
号外号外  那姑娘特可爱
Extra, extra! She's a cutie.
多谢你帮忙
Thanks for your help.
我不过弹了一段尤克里里
Hey, I just played the ukulele.
歌是你自己唱的
You sang the song.
丘比特教练
Yeah. Coach Cupid!
好了  快走吧
All right, gear.
错过公交车就麻烦了
You don't want to miss that bus.
再次感谢  盖里教练
Thanks again, Coach Gary.
他都不是你的教练
He's not even your coach.
我得喝杯威士忌连看几部007
I need a scotch and a James Bond marathon.
那你可能要失望了
You may be out of luck.
刚才电视突然坏了
The TV wasn't working a minute ago.
听起来像是卫星天线的问题
Sounds like the satellite dish.
可能是大手男乱搞我排水沟时撞歪了
Big hands probably mess it up poking around my gutters.
-让我上去看看  -别别别
- Let me check it out. - No, no, no.
可能会很危险的
That might be very dangerous.
让我去把盖里教练叫回来  让他帮你
Let me go grab Coach Gary, and he can help you.
我说了我自己去
I said I'd do it.
但我很肯定盖里教练
Yeah, but I'm sure Coach Gary
不介意多留一会的
wouldn't mind sticking around.
我自己出去修就行了
I'm getting out and pressure myself!
感谢大家来上课
Thank you all for coming.
有谁想现在就去巴黎
Who here wants to go to Paris right now?
我[法语]
Moi!
不  我们不是要真的上飞机
No. We're not getting on a plane.
这些普通的食材将带我们体验巴黎的味道
We'll be transported by these humble ingredients.
他是不是很棒
How great is he?
超棒  仔细听他说的每一句话
So great. Listen to everything he says.
看看你们的左边  再看看你们的右边
Look to your left. Look to your right.
这节课结束前
Before this class is through,
你们都会学会做伯爵烤鸡
all of you will know how to make earl roasted chicken
我知道这个食谱
Ohh! I know this recipe.
我在睡梦中也能做出来
I could make this chicken in my sleep.
咱还是醒着做吧
How about we try it awake?
让我们从最重要的食材开始  百里香
Let's start with the most important ingredient -- thyme.
没错  "白丽"美人切百里香
That's right. It's time to chop thyme.
他和电视上一样有哏
He's just like he is on TV.
是啊
Yeah.
百里香和鸡肉非常搭
Thyme and chicken play together very well,
不像狗跟鸡在一起玩[搭]那样
unlike dogs and chickens.
悲惨故事  我的救援惠比特犬与我
Tragic story, my rescue and I
住在个都市农场边上...
live next to an urban farm and...
天啊  我可以用这个作范例吗
Oh, my, do you mind if I use this as an example?
荣幸之至
Oh! Avec pleasure.
看到她怎么切这些根茎了吗
See how she's chopped it stems and all?
这是错的
That's wrong.
马虎可是会毁了这道菜
Sloppiness like this can ruin a dish.
我都不知道呢
Oh. I had no idea.
果然你在草药这一领域
I suppose when it comes to herbs, though,
你也算是鼠[尾草]一鼠二
you owe something of a sage.
-好双关  -谢谢
That's clever. Thank you.
但双关不能吃
You can't eat clever.
不许动  警察
Freeze! Police!
我是房产经纪人  不是罪犯
I'm a realtor, not a criminal.
那你当房产经纪人的功夫不够火候
Oh, well, then you're not doing it right.
吉尔
Hey, Gil.
如果你的客户真考虑
If one of your clients is actually thinking
买这块雷区的话
about buying this minefield,
那就是他们犯的第二大错
that would be their second bad decision.
-第一大是雇了你  -我猜到了
- First was hiring you. - Yeah, I got it.
你不会真劝你的客户
You're not gonna push one of your clients
买这块破地吧
into this swamp, are you?
可能它只是需要一个
Maybe it just needs a developer
有远见的开发商
with a little vision.
没啥远见  还没嗅觉
Very little vision and no sense of smell.
这块地让穷人区埃尔塞贡多
This neighborhood makes El Segundo
闻起来像美容化妆品店
seem like a Sephora.
它正处于转型期
It's in transition.
是啊  转型成费卢杰[伊拉克城市]
Yeah, it's turning into Fallujah.
我得走了  不然会被打劫的
I'm out of here before I get jacked.
-你还要在这待一阵子吗  -说不定呢
- You're gonna be around for a while? - I might.
那你可以给我搞点借代毒品美沙酮
Maybe you can score me some methadone.
鲍勃
Hey, Bob.
好消息  菲尔  他们接受了你的报价
Good news, Phil. They accepted your offer.
没有还价吗  我可能出的太高了
Without a counter? Maybe I came too high.
随便吧  他们很开心
Whatever. They were really happy.
是
Are...
等下  鲍勃  我儿子的电话
Hold on, Bob. It's my son.
卢克  怎么了
Luke, what's up?
爸
Dad?
烘衣机好像出问题了
I think something is wrong with the dryer.
但我已经修好了啊
But I-I fixed it.
好到无话可说
I fixed it good.
我马上到
I'll be right there.
快点  它好像要跑了
Hurry! I think it's leaving.
现在  这是生鲜食品
Now, this is fresh produce.
我甚至不能描述
I can't even describe...
三振出局
Strike three!
这算哪门子的提高
How exactly is this an improvement?
反正是杰选的那个灯
Jay picked that lamp.
对了  你有见到他吗
By the way. Have you seen him?
我不知道我怎么困住的
I don't know how I got stuck.
我从14岁开始就经常上房顶
I've been on roofs since I was 14 and discovered
发现那是看埃塞尔·伯京卧室最好的地点
it was the best way to see into Ethel Burkin's bedroom.
老女人  50多岁
Older gal. 50s, I think.
放到现在估计都不会多看她一眼
Today you probably wouldn't give him a second look,
但那会儿还没网络
but this was before the Internet.
不看她就得看百货内衣目录
It was either that or a Sears catalog.
我能拍个照吗
Can I take a picture of this?
有时候我朋友觉得我的故事太扯
Sometimes my friends don't believe my stories.
应该有更好的方法
There's gonna be a better way of doing this.
正相反  米奇尔
On the contrary, Mitchell.
这简单极了
It's simplicity itself.
我打掉马蜂窝  掉到垃圾桶里
I dislodge the nest. It falls into the trash can.
你盖上盖子
You close the lid.
那我们就有一桶愤怒的马蜂
Then we just have a barrel full of angry wasps.
它们会很快被送到郊外的农场
They will be swiftly transported to a farm up state
在那儿它们会更加幸福
where they'll be much happier.
它们还能见到我朋友的狗呢
Ooh, they'll see my friend's dog.
是啊  没错
Yeah, just like that.
常见的骗小孩宠物没死掉  只是送去乡下的借口
好啦  首先  我们打掉马蜂窝
All right. First, we just have to dislodge the nest.
不  不  不
No, no, no, no!
我脸上有一只  还有
There's one on my face. There's one --
别动  我被敌人发现了
Don't move. I've been compromised.
快进屋里
Get in the house!
喔  喔  喔  真是个坏主意
Ow! Ow! Oh! Ow! Ooh! Bad idea!
我本是要把你们送到农场呢
Ow! I was gonna take you to a farm!
我可能得把这个配菜的名字改为
I may have to change the name of this side dish
不"菜"的土豆烤菜
to "Potatoes au great-in."
改前改后没啥差别啊
I'm not hearing a difference.
烤"菜"双关...
Gratin...
这很独特
Oh, this is...unique.
是的  太谢谢你啦
Yes, thank you very much.
在你的节目中  你总是敢于冒险尝试
You know how on your show you were always taking chances
相信你的直觉
and trusting your instincts?
我也这么做了
Well, that is what I did.
那是因为我直觉很准
That's because I have good instincts.
你什么事做得好
What's something you do well?
烹饪
Cook?
不
No.
妈  我想他想说的是
Uh, mom, I think what he's trying to say
你应该严格按照他的食谱来做
is that you should more closely follow his recipe.
用他提到的食材
You know, use the ingredients that he mentions.
而且都该测量好
Measure stuff.
-对吧  -才不是
- Right? - Not at all.
正如我在我的第三本书
As I say in the foreword
《谁不会做饭》的前言中所说
of my third book, "Who Can't Cook?"
"有些人就是不会做饭"
"Some people can't cook."
别难过
Don't feel bad.
美食烹调很难
Gourmet cooking is tough,
不过你做的鸡肉"更难"嚼
though not as tough as your chicken.
真不敢相信会听到你这话
I can't believe I'm hearing this.
就是因为像这样的情况
It's times like this
我才希望我们有退款政策
I wish I had a refund policy.
等下
Wait a second.
我这几个月
I have been making
一直给我的家人做这些
this food for my family for months now.
每周日都做一顿大餐
I make a big meal every Sunday.
我是上班族妈妈
I'm a working mom.
这是我一周中为家人做些什么
It's my one chance a week to give my family something
弥补我错过的时光的唯一机会
and make up for the time I haven't spent with them.
你是在告诉我  我一直在给我家人做垃圾吗
Are you telling me I've been giving my family garbage?
等下
Wait, uh...
海莉  亲爱的
Haley, honey,
我给你做的是垃圾吗
have I been serving you garbage?
你觉得我会说什么
What do you think I said?
她是最好的厨师
She is the best cook ever.
我们喜欢她做的所有的菜
We love all of her meals.
-是不是像音乐一样悦耳  -太棒了
- Am I singing? - So good.
太
So...
杰
Jay?
Jay!
我在上面
I'm up here.
我的天啊  天妒英才  英年早逝啊
Ay, Dios mio! Your time was too short!
我在屋顶
I'm on the roof.
好的
Ah. Oh, okay.
下来吧  电视已经好了
So come down because the TV's working already.
我很享受待在这儿
You know, I'm kind of enjoying hanging out up here.
等会儿我再下去
I-I'll be down in a little bit.
如果乔想锻炼投球的手臂
Hey, if Joe wants to work on his throwing arm,
他可以投个空瓶子上来
maybe he can toss up, uh, an empty bottle.
你被困在上面了吗
Are you stuck up there?
困住  才没有
Stuck? No!
我随时想下来就可以下来
I can come down whenever I want to.
我只要把身体挂到天台边缘
I just have to... dangle my body out over the edge
然后凭感觉踩上
and then reach blindly
不应该踩的梯子最顶端那一阶就行了
for that top rung of the ladder you're not supposed to use.
但我等会再回去
But I'll be in in a little bit.
我这还有些事要搞定
I got a few things I got to do.
我得先保养一下这个房顶
Got to maintain the roof.
这可是你家房子的帽子
It's your house's hat.
我打电话给了一个
I called the one person
我绝不可能在他面前感到丢脸的人
I couldn't possibly be embarrassed in front of.
外公的电话
It's grandpa.
不要接  不能让他知道这件事
Don't answer! He can't know about this.
我们有一个基本上是因为我有能力
We have a verbal contract that's largely based
修好烘干机才达成的口头协议
on my ability to fix dryers.
拜托一定要好
Please work.
成功了
Yes!
..吧
Maybe.
-那是什么味道  -失败的味道
- What's that smell? - Failure.
小卡  那个蛰伤看起来挺严重的
Oh, Cam, that sting looks really bad.
我们应该带你找个医生看看
We -- We should get you to a doctor.
被马蜂蜇[上流人笑]就找医生吗
A doctor for a wasps sting?
WASP: 原指殖民时代来自英国的新教上流社会移民
这类白人常带有种族主义  排外主义  反同  文化种族优越感
行啊  让我们戴上大礼帽
Yes, let's put on our top hats
在去的路上再吃点英国小圆饼
and eat crumpets while we're on our way.
好啦  我知道你觉得自觉言之有理
Okay, I know you think you're making a point.
以前在农场的时候
Back on the farm,
每次我们除掉马蜂窝的时候
every time we would take down a wasp nest,
我总是要被蛰一下
I would get stung.
这事你应该提前说的
Something you might have mentioned.
我从没需要擦过那些高级的药膏
And never once did I need fancy medicine.
就是抹上一点泥
Just a little mud.
没错  莉莉
That's right, Lily.
大爸就是这么自立自强
Daddy's being self-reliant.
你觉得他说的泥有几成机率是指真的泥土
What do you think the chances are he means actuall mud?
几率非常高
Pretty good.
就像我阿姨多特说过的
Like my Aunt Dot said,
"不论是被蜜蜂蛰了还是背疼
"Whether it's bee stings or back aches,
一点泥巴就可以帮助你缓解疼痛"
a little mud is good for what ails you."
我怎么不记得见过哪个多特阿姨
I don't remember meeting an Aunt Dot.
她已经去世了
She died.
15分钟后
15 minutes later.
好吧
All right.
我想我给你做了一点
I thought I'd make you a little bit --
要了亲命
Oh, my God!
咋了  我的脸吗
What? My face?
很糟糕吗  我感觉很糟糕
Is it bad? It feels bad.
它看上去有一点像
It looks a little like
电影里人的脸被融化掉的样子
you stared directly into the Lost Ark.
-我想照镜子看看  -你不会想看到的
- I want to see. - You don't.
你觉得会不会是因为我擦了泥才让它恶化了
Do you think maybe me putting mud on it made it worse?
我是不知道把脏兮兮的泥土直接擦在伤口上...
I don't know how putting dirt directly into a wound --
会不..会  你要去哪
It -- It -- Where are you going?
去找医生  我想要重新找回我的颜值
To the doctor. I want to be pretty again.
好吧  那咱们不自力更生了吗
Well, w-what about being self-reliant?
伤的是人家的脸蛋啊  快点啦
It's my face! Let's go!
马蜂  它们还在门外
Wasps! They're still out there!
可以  我能等
Yeah, I'll hold.
我要撤回这笔交易
I'm pulling out of the deal.
为什么  怎么啦
Why? What happened?
我并不是你心目中那
I'm not the man you thought
大白天跟你滚床单的霸气男人
you had middle of the day sex with.
亲爱的  我听说烘干机的事了
Honey, I heard about the dryer.
不只是因为这个
It's not just that.
我还遇到格尔  他觉得这是自寻死路
I ran into Gil. He thinks it's a bad idea.
我也得顾虑你爸投进来的钱
Your dad's money is on the line.
我从没做过像这样的事
I've never done anything like this.
谁管格尔·索普觉得怎么样
Who cares what Gil Thorpe thinks?
世上没人比你还懂房地产不是吗
Nobody knows more about real estate than you do,
而且你已经琢磨这项目很久了
and you've been thinking about this project for a long time.
我对你有信心
I believe in you.
你也应该对自己有信心
You should believe in yourself.
鲍伯
Yeah, hey, Bob.
是菲尔
It's Phil.
删除掉抽身条款吧  咱们干到底
Remove the contingencies. Let's do this.
这是真的吗
Is that a fact?
感谢你告诉我这事
Thanks for letting me know.
格尔·索普也给了个后备开价
Gil Thorpe made a backup offer.
他只是想把我给吓走
He was just trying to scare me away.
我真是以你为荣
Oh! I am so proud of you!
貌似我们两个
Wow. Looks like the both of us had
今天都遇到了一点信心危机
a little crisis of confidence today.
今天上烹饪班时...
In my cooking classs...
-然后呢  -是这样的
- Yes? - Yes, well,
杜蒙特大厨居然大言不惭说
Chef Dumont had the audacity
我压根就不是块做饭的料
to tell me that I can't cook.
幸好  有她在现场反驳了他的屁话
Luckily, this one was there to straighten him out.
我要给你做一顿庆祝晚餐
I'm gonna make you a celebratory dinner.
我觉得我应该有大多数材料了
I think I've got most of the ingredients.
我真是等不及啦
I can't wait! Mm-hmm.
就给了你一个任务
You had one job.
杰
Hi, Jay.
靠  她打给你搬救兵了
Oh, crap. She called you.
手给我
Give me your hand.
为啥  好让你再羞辱我一次吗
Why? So you can show me up again?
你在说什么呢
What are you talking about?
你就省省吧
Give it a rest.
大摇大摆带着你那强健的年轻肩膀
You come in here with your young shoulders,
还有尤克里里来显摆
your ukulele.
杰  我从来没有想要羞辱你啊
I'm not trying to show you up, Jay.
我是想给你制造好印象
I'm trying to impress you.
你为毛会想给我制造好印象啊
Why the heck would you want to do that?
其实跟你现在有点像
I guess you could say like you,
我在自己的事上有点搁浅了
I'm stranded in my own way.
我实在很不喜欢这么说话
This is my least-favorite way of talking.
杰  我老实告诉你
I got to tell you, Jay,
我想退出运动界了
I'm over the whole sports thing.
可你才刚赢得冠军啊
But you just won the championship.
没错
Exactly.
对我来说世上已无龙可斩
And there's no more Dragons to slay.
这不是比喻  我是指去年打败的队
That's the team we beat last year --
淡蓝宝宝龙
the Baby Blue Dragons.
我还是完全没懂你啥意思
I'm not seeing how I figure into this.
我想自己创业
I want to start my own business.
而你是成功多年的前辈
You've been so successful.
我在想或许能找你当我的导师
I was thinking maybe you could be my mentor.
哪方面的生意
What line of work?
预组装凉亭
Pre-fab gazebos.
赞耶
Nice!
把每家的后院变成自家的市中心广场
Every backyard could be its own town square.
我就知道你会懂
I knew you'd get it.
毕竟  所有的凉亭
After all, what's a gazebo but...
-都是户外的衣柜嘛  -户外的衣柜嘛
- An outdoor closet! - an outdoor closet?
你还行  盖里教练
You're all right, Coach Gary.
手给我  帮忙我下来
Give me your hand. Help me down.
我们一起喝两杯  然后咱们谈谈生意
We'll get a few drinks, and we'll talk business.
盖里的凉亭
Gary's Gazebos.
盖里家凉亭
Gazebos by Gary.
盖里家凉亭与工具棚
Gary's Gazebos and Sheds.
你都不需要请教我
You don't need me.
好啦
All right.
这是你独自坐在空荡荡后院
Is this you sitting alone in an empty yard
幻想着如果你有...
wishing you had....
一个凉亭
...a gazebo...
或工具棚的样子吗
...or a shed?
如果是你  请致电盖里家凉亭与工具棚
If it is, then call Gary's Gazebos and Sheds.
因为在这里  我们只致力于一件事
Because here, we only do one thing --
贩卖  安装
...sell, install,
与保养凉亭与工具棚
and service gazebos and sheds.
也欢迎询问花园小鸟水盆啊
And ask about our bird baths.
我们有这生意一成股份呢
We own 10% of that, you know.
你花了多少钱投资这生意啊
How much money did you put into the businesses?
反正我钱财生不带来死不带去
Well, you can't take it with you.
可是我们其他几个都会健在呢
But we'll all still be here!